<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>About on CWRU Grappling Club</title>
    <link>http://example.org/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on CWRU Grappling Club</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:24:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What Is Grappling?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/what-is-grappling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 10:08:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/what-is-grappling/</guid>
      <description>What is Grappling?  grappling is defined as a struggle or fight without weapons. The closest mainstream sport is wrestling. The term can apply to any combat sport that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use strikes (punches / kicks) and instead focuses on control or submissions. Grappling is most commonly used to describe Brazilian Jiu Jitsu practiced without the gi jacket ie &amp;ldquo;nogi&amp;rdquo;. For the club we chose nogi because the gi incurs cost and cleaning that stands as a barrier of entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Try Grappling?</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/why-try-grappling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 10:11:30 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/why-try-grappling/</guid>
      <description>Why try grappling, gi or nogi? There are three main reasons that someone would train grappling
 For self defense  Because grappling doesn&amp;rsquo;t injure your training partner, only controls them or puts them in a submission hold where they can &amp;ldquo;tap out&amp;rdquo; before they experience harm or injury, you can spar at 100% preparing yourself for the intensity of a real physical conflict without harming yourself or others. Grappling exchanges are also extremely effective for fighting and in MMA wrestling / Jiu Jitsu is an integral part of training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/safety/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 10:21:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/safety/</guid>
      <description>Safety  sports, especially combat sports are hard, physically taxing, and can lead to injuries when done with  Poor instruction No supervision too much ego not enough respect for your training partners   when it comes to grappling sports in particular it is hard to learn in a vacuum. We need training partners to train (that&amp;rsquo;s why their called training partners!). This means that there must be mutual respect between training partners.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Classes</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/our-classes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 10:12:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/our-classes/</guid>
      <description>what specifically will we teach?  We will be trying to teach to people of any level. Naturally most of the members will be beginners so a huge emphasis will be on the fundamentals. Some of the founders of the club have a strong leg lock backgrounds so we will focus on integrating leg locks from the ground up in a safe and systematic manner. Because two of the founders have strong wrestling backgrounds we will spend the beginning of classes working takedowns  class breakdown  Warm up through drills and or movement training (~10min) Working floor to feet takedowns (~10min) working ground techniques (~15min) rolling (sparring) (~15-20min)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
